[Music]
this is software engineering radio the
podcast for professional developers on
the web at se-radio.net
sc radio is brought to you by the ieee
computer society by ieee software
magazine
online at computer.org software
con 42 is a new series of must-watch
tech conferences it's online and free to
attend with hybrid events coming next
year com 42 conferences cover topics
like cloud sre chaos engineering machine
learning and quantum computing as well
as programming languages including
python golang rust and javascript
register for free at con42.com
sc radio that's
number four number two dot com slash
s-e-radio
see you there for the ultimate answers
this is philip winston for software
engineering radio my guest today is paul
butcher paul is a senior software
engineer at adacore and their lead
engineer in the uk for their high class
initiative
prior to joining adacore paul was a
consultant software engineer for 10
years working for aerospace companies
such as leonardo helicopters bae systems
and talus uk
before becoming a consultant paul worked
on the typhoon platform and safety
critical software for military uavs
welcome paul hi philip welcome to you
thanks for inviting me on the show
so i think our listeners are familiar
with a lot of different types of testing
but perhaps not fuzz testing can you
tell me what fuzz testing is
absolutely so one nice way to think
about what fuzz testing is is to
consider how it differs to standard
verification testing
so if we considered we have a software
application it has an input and it's
going to generate an output
then we can test that by having a test
case that has an actual input and a
correlating expected output and then we
execute the test and we check that the
actual output matched the expected
output
fuzz testing differs in that we're not
so interested in the output of the
application
we're more interested in the behavior
and it's the
the behavior of the software application
as we
we subject it to a number of different
inputs that it may not even be
used to dealing with
so is that considered negative testing i
read about positive and negative testing
i wondered how that related to fuzz test
yeah it is related so positive testing i
consider that to be
more verification based so we have some
requirements that our system has to
satisfy
and we can build up evidence to argue
that we've met those requirements
through
positive testing mechanisms
i guess a way of considering this would
be
we have a secure room that we want to
test that the the entrance mechanism to
this room
works correctly and a positive way of
testing this would be to take all of the
authorized personnel
and have them line up and let's see if
they can indeed open this door and go
through it the flip side of that to look
at it from a negative testing aspect
would be to take
every single human being that isn't
authorized to enter this room have them
line up and let's observe that they
can't get in and you know here lies in
the problem of negative testing you can
immediately see that the the number of
potential test cases can be very large
if not indefinitely large
okay that makes sense and i'm going to
list a few practices that i discovered
in my research and we can go through
them one by one to see how they connect
to fuzz testing or if they do
so i think the four practices i i saw
are safety engineering
security engineering robustness
engineering and vulnerability testing
and feel free to lump these into
categories or divide them up differently
but let's start with
safety engineering what does that mean
to you
for me
safety engineering is producing if we're
talking in the software sense it's
producing a software system
that
is
responsible for a critical aspect of the
the application
that should that
aspect fail
there will be a high chance of a loss of
life and
you know this is very
prominent in the aerospace industry a
safety engineering would play a key role
in the
flight management system the avionics of
the aircraft and
first testing can play a role here but
it's
more traditionally associated with
security testing but of course the
disciplines do overlap so if you have a
vulnerability within your system that
can be exploited
and
that can lead on to a safety implication
it could trigger a sequence of events
that could lead to a safety hazard
then fuss testing could identify that
vulnerability
so you touched on security engineering
my
feeling there is that's
more in line with an actual attempt to
subvert the software an attacker is that
what security means in that context
we tend to think of
our software systems as if they're
security critical they need to be
free of exploitable vulnerabilities and
that ties into vulnerability testing so
i guess these are sort of overlapping
categories but i was interested in your
definition of safety that's a more dire
sense of safety than i've dealt with in
my own applications so how about
robustness engineering that was the
fourth one on the list
i think it depends on
the certification you're trying to
achieve with your software system
my experience tends to come with
defense and aerospace and we have
guidelines like d0178c
which is a guideline for producing
safe software systems
robustness engineering does come under
d178c but it's more of a requirements
based
activity and it's
perhaps not
suitable to satisfy those objectives
with first testing so i would say first
testing is is more for vulnerability
identification and once you've
identified a vulnerability in your
system
depending on where you are in your
software development life cycle you may
be able to
correct that vulnerability
but if you can't and you've identified
it then you'll need to put security
measures in place and fuzz testing can
also play a role in
determining whether those security
measures are sufficient for protecting
your security assets
so you touched upon something i was
wondering which is if fuzz testing finds
a crash in an application it's able to
produce a crash
is determining whether that crash is
exploitable whether it's a real
vulnerability is that part of the fuzz
testing or do you sort of hand that off
to a second type of
testing which digs into these issues
that you
so found
that is a great question and i think
it's dependent on
the particular capability there are
commercial fuzz testing tools out there
that
have that mechanism they can identify
vulnerabilities and then produce
exploitations and
try and see dynamically whether that
vulnerability is exploitable that's
quite advanced fuzz testing
typically it's
a mechanism for identifying bugs within
your system
regardless of whether those bugs can be
exploited or not and i would argue that
most software bugs should be fixed there
needs to be a very good reason for
having software bugs within your system
so there's a benefit in identifying them
regardless of whether they're
exploitable or not
i can see that
and you mentioned the software
development life cycle when in your
projects have you employed fuzz testing
is it early or late in the process
we're looking at it from
more of a developer's
perspective
and
from my experience it tends to come into
play much later in the software
development life cycle
and i've spoken to companies that have
fuzz testing teams
that will build up the fuzz testing
campaigns and they'll be given a
software system prior to deployment and
they will do their security analysis at
that point like all testing the earlier
you can
get it into the development life cycle
the more benefit you're going to get
from the capability
so maybe before we dive into
the details of fuzz testing you could
just relate an anecdote or a story about
a time that fuzz testing found a
surprising vulnerability or i know you
may not be able to give us all the
details but something that surprised you
that you wouldn't have been able to
sort of discover on your own yeah
absolutely i first came into contact
with this
technology
it was about three years ago during my
interview process with adacor the
company that i'm with now and i was
asked if what my understanding of fuzz
testing was and i
didn't have a huge amount so i was given
the
the task of going away
and investigating fuzz testing with the
aim of
presenting back my research as part of
the interview process
and
whilst doing that i took a
software application that i found on an
open source piece of software on the web
that read an xml file it verified that
xml against an xml schema did some
processing on the data and produced some
output
after setting up the first testing
harness and executing the first test
i left it running for three days
and it came back with a test case that
was crashing the system
and on further inspection
it was producing a valid xml file
where one of the data elements
should have been identified by the
schema as being
invalid data
and
once i started investigating further it
turned out that it was a fault within a
regular expression library
and
this was interesting to me because
this is kind of the journey that fuzz
testing can often take you on isn't the
one you expect to go on rather than find
a bug within the actual software system
it was a bug within a secondary library
that the software system that was using
okay building off that can you walk us
through a typical fuzz testing scenario
from the start in terms of the
developers experience what tools do they
specifically use or could use
and how much time is spent setting
things up versus actually running
the testing
and and maybe a final thing there is do
you use local testing resources or is
this something can be done in the cloud
or needs to be done in the cloud based
on the amount of computation needed
there is always effort involved in
setting up a fuzz testing campaign i
would say it's proportionate to the
amount of time you then need to spend
leaving the test executing the actual
measurements of time are going to be
based on the complexity of the system
you're testing and indeed the complexity
of the
input data that that
software application receives but a
typical
scenario for a developer who wants to
first test some software
would be they would
choose a fuzz testing tool a typical
open source first testing tool that is i
would say is regarded as the de facto
fuzz testing capability out there
is american fuzzy lop or afl which is a
fuzzing engine that's come out of google
labs the software developer would need
to identify the test injection point
so this is
a definition
of the input data into this system needs
to be understood such that
the the developer can build
a starting corpus and what we mean here
is that
we need to provide the fuzz testing
engine
with
an initial set of test cases
that it can then work on and mutate such
that it can produce more test cases and
inject them into the system
whilst observing the behavior of the
system and detecting if there any
crashes or
hung processes have occurred
so you mentioned mutation and i read a
little bit about a mutation engine is
that what afl is is it generating these
test cases by mutation
afl is a really good example of a
mutation based test case generation
strategy
so mutation algorithms differ from
a much simpler form of fuzz testing that
is commonly known as brute force or
black box
testing
or even blunt force and this is where
you're
just producing random inputs to fire
into your software system
and
typically
a large proportion of those
randomly generated test cases are going
to be
syntactically invalid and your software
system is going to
throw them away at the boundary and
that's not to say there isn't a benefit
in
testing the interface of a system in in
a brute force way but what gets more
interesting is when we introduced
introduced mutation based strategies
and this allows us to get much deeper
into the control flow of the software
application
so one thing i was thinking about with
this brute force testing is it's really
not possible to try all possible inputs
if the input to your function or your
network packet is even
one 64-bit integer
there's trillions upon trillions of
possible values so
is brute force necessarily testing only
a small subset because the name you
might think it's testing all possible
inputs
it's a really good observation that it's
not a great name and that's typically
why i tend to prefer
thinking of it more of as blunt force
you're absolutely right you
you very very quickly start riding the
steep incline of an exponential curve
when you
have complex data inputs
and it doesn't take much for you to
to start
getting to a point where even with
something like quantum computing and a
huge amount of resources and time you
still won't get anywhere near the number
of test case permutations
i guess a good analogy of this is the
infinite monkey theory where if you take
an infinite number of monkeys give them
all a typewriter eventually they will
produce the full works of shakespeare
but in reality
even if you filled the the entire
observable universe with monkeys and
typewriters you're probably not going to
get hamlet out at any any point in the
near future and perhaps a better way of
doing it would be to give the monkeys a
library of texts and let's see if they
can produce some interesting
novels
by taking those texts and swapping words
around them
this is the direct benefit of mutation
algorithms
okay so let's go back to the example of
the developer performing fuzz testing
once everything is set up
and say you do find a crash
and then the other developers or you
iterate to you know mitigate that crash
is it pretty easy to rerun the fuss
testing or do you have to kind of start
over
setting things up
ordinarily it is easy if you're using an
approach like afl it will build up a set
of test cases that it considers
interesting as it's executing and you
can pull those test cases out of
of its queue
and they become the starting corpus for
the next test run
so you can kind of kick off where you
left
and in terms of duration how long
in hours or days have you seen the time
period that you need to execute the fuzz
testing whether it's afl or some other
system how long typically do you want
these execution times to be
you ultimately want to be able to
identify as many vulnerabilities as you
feasibly can within a short amount of
space of time that's that's the goal of
this
it's going to be very much dependent on
the complexity of the system
and the capability
of the first testing mechanism that
you're using there are ways of speeding
up that process by using additional side
tools like symbolic execution or other
tools that
allow you to instrument the code and
give you a sense of a feedback loop such
that you can understand when you've hit
new paths through the execution
so i read a little bit about divergent
paths and you mentioned code
instrumentation what type of
instrumentation are we doing here is it
a question of
adding calls to a library or
marking up the code how invasive is this
instrumentation
the way
afl does this and this is where we're
we're typically talking about smart gray
box first testing
and just to break that term down it's
it's gray box in the sense that we have
an understanding we need to go inside
the application and add some
instrumentation we're not white box
because we don't understand the
functional behavior of the program and
we're not blackbox
and what afl will do is that
during the compilation phase there's a
compiler pass that adds instrumentation
points
around the basic blocks of the code
and what these instrumentation points
are doing is they are writing into a
shared memory area and they're basically
incrementing a value within a buffer and
as the test is executing these values
will be incremented and this allows the
fuzzing engine to understand when a new
path of execution has just been found
through the control flow graph
of the program you're testing and it
will then take that test case and say
well you made progress you got us deeper
into the into the diverging paths within
this application i'm going to put you
back on the queue and mutate you further
that's very interesting so
you're able to detect that this test
case has found a new path in the code
and now you want to explore even deeper
and maybe find yet another or follow-on
path so without this instrumentation is
the only thing you can do with a fuzz
test is check if the application has
crashed or are you looking at the output
of the application to see that you've
altered it in general but here we're
talking about the anomaly
detection capability of a first testing
campaign you commonly are checking for
if the progress has crashed but there's
a lot more we can actually do here
there's always a very easy or very crude
way of detecting whether the program is
hung in that we can just have a timeout
on the execution and say well if it
exceeded so long we'll call it a hung
process
if you start to look at the runtime
exception
checking that many programming languages
have then
there are additional constraints we can
check as that program's executing and
typically here
we can identify buffer overflows or
buffer underflows
that actually may not have caused the
execution to crash you could have a
buffer overflow that writes into the
next area of stack but the program is
now operating in an unknown and
potentially dangerous state but it's
still running and it's still
it hasn't crashed yet and
things like using an address sanitizer
can identify that yeah that's
interesting i can see there's a lot to
study the results of these fuzz tests
and to determine the best technique
going forward
today's sponsor is spot by netapp the
cloud automation platform that makes it
easy to deliver continuously optimized
infrastructure at the lowest possible
cost
get the most out of your cloud
investments by automating cloud
infrastructure to ensure performance
reduce complexity and optimize costs
their machine learning and automation
scale to exactly meet application needs
using the most efficient mix of
instances and pricing models eliminating
the risks of over-provisioning and cloud
waste
leverage spot with all leading cloud
platforms services and tools
check them out at spot.io
se radio where you can find more
information request a demo or even start
a free trial
[Music]
i guess to go back to duration what
would you consider a very long fuzz
testing process are we talking about
is this something you would parallelize
with multiple instances or is it
how do you scale up this testing if you
do have long durations that you need to
test over
if you're looking at
first testing a complex system then
you'll need to accept that it may take a
long time and you can reduce that time
by
executing multiple fuzzing sessions at
the same time so you can utilize a
multi-core system
and run a fuzzer on each core
typically this will be done in a
high-end server away from the developers
workstation
maybe via a continuous integration
mechanism there's ways of
invoking first tests on software
applications as pull requests are
submitted into
you know git repositories and things
like that
but if it's a complicated system
you could be
expected to to execute for
days
before you see anything useful back
yeah so in that case it's maybe not part
of the continuous integration with every
check-in but it's run at some other
interval or it's run sort of as often as
it can what is a fork server and it
sounds like that might
relate to the specifics of testing a
running application or scaling up the
testing
one of the aspects of fuzz testing that
you need to
achieve is a very very fast
mutation phase and a very fast injection
of that test case into the software
system and then you want that
software execution to be very quick we
need to accept here that we're going to
be producing a lot of test cases that
may be invalid and a lot of test cases
that may not be particularly interesting
so we want to get through them as quick
as we can to try and get to the real
juicy interesting stuff so this tends to
be a mechanism that's built into an
operating system and allows you to
to spawn processes
and
first testing is all about the
generation of test cases and the
injection of those test cases into a
software application as fast as possible
and
we need it to be fast because
a large proportion of those test cases
may be invalid in that they're going to
get thrown away at the boundary of the
system or they may just not be
interesting and they may not be taking
us to new areas of the program
so a fork server is typically used to
spawn a new process and in this case
it's the software application under test
and then we will inject the test case
into that process and observe the
behavior of the test
there are ways of moving away from that
mechanism and afl offers up a persistent
test case mode where you can
run multiple tests within the same
process and this rapidly speeds up the
testing but then there are complexities
evolved with
the retained state of the software
application in between test runs
let's talk about an endeavor that i
think your company is involved with and
see how it relates to fuzz testing and
how it maybe relates to other software
practices for high availability high
critical systems so i came upon this
acronym high class
and i'll read what it stands for high
integrity complex large software and
electronic systems is this something
that relates to fuzz testing or is it a
bigger endeavor than that
it's a
bigger endeavor than that it's
a uk government sponsored research and
development programme
that
has a main focus on cyber security
within civilian aerospace so the goal
behind high class is to bring together
tier one aerospace manufacturers within
the uk
and
tool providers
like adacore but also
universities
and the research group is split into a
number of work packages that are looking
at things like
cyber security within the aerospace
industry as far as guidelines and
standards go
and then there's aspects of how to
implement security measures for the
industry how to detect vulnerabilities
which is where things like fuzz testing
come in there's other aspects of the
research program as well that other
people are working on what is the term
compiler hardening and how does that
relate to these efforts
so compiler hardening is
and i probably should start this by
saying that
one of the main areas of development
tools that adacore works in is compilers
we we produce compilers for ada c and c
plus plus across multiple platforms
compiler hardening is a mechanism for
accepting that the
the generated
software system that the compiled
software system could be subjected to
hardware attacks
and things like side channel attacks and
what we're
looking into is whether we can add
security measures at the compiler level
and that
can counter measure these particular
type of security attacks
an example of this is clearing the stack
on a function exit and ensuring that you
know valuable data can't be read from
those memory areas
maybe this segways into
formal methods that's another term that
i came across related to high class
feeling it doesn't directly relate to
fuzz testing but maybe it's in the same
category of you know extensive involved
processes that we can do to guarantee
critical software functions correctly
have you come across formal methods yeah
absolutely and
it fits within high class in that
we very much think of security measures
as being a layered
approach we talk about defense in depth
with security we accept that one
security measure may not be enough and
things like common mode failures
which are all about one attack bringing
down multiple security measures
formal methods
is
a way of
mathematically proving that your
software application is functionally
correct and
absent of runtime errors and
if you can take some high crit
the high critical aspects of the
application and formally prove them to
be functionally correct and bug free and
then some of the lower criticality
aspects you can fuzz test them
and gain assurance
that your um system is secure you can
come up with a convincing argument that
your overall system is secure
great that makes sense
so we've talked about fuzz testing and
we talked about this high class
initiative the name of your company is
adacore we haven't talked about ada
that's a programming language i use very
briefly in school but i have not seen a
lot recently can you tell me what
domains ada is is still used today or
whether you consider it a language
that's still under active development or
is it in a different stage of its life
so it's still very much in active
development
and
my own experience is i i studied aida at
university the first job that i had was
an ada based program working on the
eurofighter program and i then went
through
a bit of a pilgrimage of working on
multiple different programming languages
before coming back to working on ada
again
and
my personal experience is that it's a
it's a fantastic language but
you tend to see it in
software applications that
have a either
a mission critical safety critical or
security critical need
it's widely used within the defense
industry within across europe and the
u.s and and all over the world the
automotive sector and the rail industry
nuclear space
as a language the reference manual is a
is an iso standard and there's a an iso
working group that are
constantly working on improvements to
the language
to ensure it stays competitive with the
other capabilities of the other existing
languages out there so you mentioned you
your company makes compilers for ada but
also c and c plus plus it seems like
this would give you a perspective
if we tie it back to fuzz testing how
does fuzz testing strategies or
capabilities
differ between those three languages
this is a really interesting subject for
me ada has a very rich
runtime testing capability that's built
into the semantics of the is defined
within that iso standard that if you're
going to write an ada compiler you have
to have runtime constraint checking for
buffer overflows
and it's a strongly typed language so if
you try to
if you try to mix types in assignment
calls the runtime is going to pick up on
that and what this runtime does is that
it will raise exceptions if the runtime
any of the runtime checks fail we can
capture these within the test harness
our fuzz test harness and we can
indicate to the fuzzing application that
a runtime check has failed so what you
typically tend to do is you you switch
on as many of the runtime checks as you
can before executing the fuzz test and
this is where we can not only just check
for crashes
we can check for
the system
having entered an unknown operating
state
in addition
programming languages that support a
design by contract
capability are really interesting for
first testing
if you're first testing a c application
you could write you could put assertions
in there to say
if this happens raise this assertion
the first test will pick that up as an
anomaly and it will give you the test
case to reproduce it in ada you can
write
pre and post condition contracts
on your subprograms within your
application so a typical example is if
you've
a very simplistic example if you have a
subprogram that takes two parameters
and returns their
summation then
your post condition would say the output
has to be equal to
the two inputs when they're added
together if that contract fails the
runtime check will detect that and
the first test will pick up on it this
is where we can start to move towards
some aspects of first testing for
functional correctness as well
so talking about ada's capabilities for
reliability and safety and security
to what degree would you say those
features are coming from the language
itself and to what degree are they sort
of layers of effort that are going on
top of the language such as fuzz testing
or formal methods
some aspects of the language are there
to
ensure that the developer writes their
code in a very structured way and
there are
lots of aspects of the semantics of the
language
that stop you from doing things that
you may not have even appreciated could
be non-secure or unsafe
and typically these are things like the
strong typing mechanism that ada
supports and aspects like the
extensive runtime checking but in
addition to that if you want to get to
the highest level of assurance for your
software system and this is where we're
talking about mainly safety critical
software so
an example could be an emergency braking
system on an automated train
where it just absolutely has to work
this is where tools like spark play a
role and
spark is a
it's a language in its own right and
that it's a subset of ada but it's also
a static analysis capability that
can analyze the code and tell you
whether it's functionally correct and
absent of runtime errors
okay great i wanted to ask about your
cnc plus plus compilers but i was
wondering if you had to cite a drawback
of development in ada what would you say
is a challenge or a negative i say the
language itself
my personal experiences it's
it's great i love developing an ada the
issue
that we we actively work on is is
building the community of ada developers
and there is a community out there
but where other languages
perhaps like c plus plus and java have
have grown in a huge way in there there
are more extensive resources available
we've got to put more effort into
ensuring the same resources are
available for ada and they are but it
would be nice to grow that community
more
so moving on to the cnc plus plus
compilers what features does adacore add
that maybe is not available in the
typical compiler
i would say and i should probably caveat
this with that i'm not an expert in the
cnc plus plus compilers
we have some quite interesting
technology around
converting
ada programs to c programs and vice
versa and what this capability allows
you to do is that you can
you can use the formal proof
tools on the ada version and then you
can
cross com you could generate that ada
into c and then you can cross compile
that
on a on a processor that perhaps
an ada compiler wasn't supported on
so we've talked about ada and c and c
plus plus let's move on to
just to mention a little bit about other
languages you may or may not be
personally familiar with these but what
is the role of fuzz testing in so-called
safe languages like javascript python
rust or go where the runtime is not
supposed to allow buffer overflows and
overruns is there still a role for fuzz
testing in these languages
there absolutely is i would say because
although the runtime doesn't allow these
things to happen
i believe what we're talking about here
is that the runtime can detect that
these things has happened and what we
don't have is the capability to detect
it's going to happen at the compile time
and i mean you you get some sense of
this with some compilers they may issue
warnings to say
hold on this is looking a bit dodgy what
you're trying to do here or you can run
static analysis that can identify these
sort of issues but if we're relying on
the runtime to catch them
then we need something like a fuzzer to
trigger those events
great okay now let's start wrapping up
what would you say is the future of fuzz
testing or
some endeavors that you think are
promising or
interesting in the in related to the
field looking out say a few years from
now where would you like to see the
practice of fuzz testing so for me
the research that's going into this area
is is incredible it's a very hot topic
in the future i would expect
much more automation
anything that
takes away the complexity of setting up
the test is is definitely a step in the
right direction and then in addition
you've got supporting tools like
symbolic execution that can
can help you explore more of that code
base and
i think we touched on diverging paths
and symbolic execution is a mechanism
that can get you through bottlenecks
in your control flow so an example would
be an if statement that says if variable
x equals
some
obscure floating point number that's
quite difficult for a fuzz test mutation
algorithm
to randomly stumble across that number
to be able to get through that
bottleneck whereas
symbolic execution allows you to
symbolically execute a program
and then when you get to a divergence
it can use
theorem solvers like microsoft said
three tool
to take the execution back to the
starting point and calculate what the
input
should have been to take you down the
diverging branch
and
these capabilities can suffer from
issues like branch explosion and you
know the amount of memory that they can
consume while they're executing and the
length of time it can take to solve the
inputs to
determine the inputs that you need
can be quite long
but they're being actively worked on and
i'd expect these capabilities to improve
in the future as well
for me combining fuzz testing
with
other techniques like symbolic execution
is really going to be where the future
goes that sounds really promising is
there anything we haven't talked about
that you'd like to bring up at this
point
there's one aspect of first testing that
we're researching at the moment that i'm
quite interested in and this is
moving away from
fuzz testing at the system level
and
taking the capability
and moving it more towards the hands of
the developer what we're looking at
producing here is a technique that
allows the developer to get to a point
where he's his code is compiling but
it's not ready to be
identified as a full system yet but
there is aspects of it that are working
whether we can then identify
functions within the program that we can
fuzz test
and we then
are looking at building a tool that can
produce values for the parameters of
those functions
from the the first test mutation engine
and
this opens up quite a lot of
potential for the technology because you
can scope the tests to whatever level
you want you don't have to be doing it
the system level you can tighten it up
to a subsystem or even a very small
sub program
where can listeners find out more about
you ada core or fuzz testing in general
and i'll put the links in the show notes
we've got a few blog posts that we've
produced about the the first testing
work we're doing there's the blog post
is
ada call
if you do a search for adacore blogs
there's a whole host of blogs up there
that
our engineers produce on a regular basis
the company website is an excellent way
to find out more about what we're doing
great i'll look up those urls and put
them in the show notes
so let me mention three previous shows
that might be related there was 453
aaron reinhardt on security chaos
engineering 390 sam proctor on security
and software design and 309 zane lackey
on application security
okay well i think that wraps it up paul
thanks a lot for your insights here and
it was nice to have you on the show
oh thank you philip that was an absolute
pleasure and to thank you for taking the
time to invite me on the show this is
phillip winston for software engineering
radio
sc radio listeners we want to hear from
you
please visit
se-radio.net survey to share a little
information about your professional
interests and listening habits it takes
less than two minutes to help us
continue to make se radio even better
your responses to the survey are
completely confidential that's
s-e-radio.net survey
thanks for your support of the show we
look forward to hearing from you soon
[Music]
thanks for listening to sc radio an
educational program brought to you by
ieee software magazine for more about
the podcast including other episodes
visit our website at se radio.net
to provide feedback you can comment on
each episode on the website or reach us
on linkedin facebook twitter or through
our slack channel at se radio dot slack
you can also email us at team
sc-radio.net
this and all other episodes of sc radio
is licensed under creative commons
license 2.5
thanks for listening